Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair;
But I cannot sever the tangled threads on my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Your Majesty, His Majesty is back from the Temple of Pure Dew.
At this hour...
Just in time to invite His Majesty over for dinner.
His Majesty said that he is tired,
and exempted concubines from paying respects today.
His Majesty is now resting in the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
Longtaitou Festival is an important day.
Surely His Majesty will stay in my palace tonight.
How come ...
Go inquire if anything went amiss today at the Temple of Pure Dew.
I already have, Your Majesty.
But His Majesty's direct servants were very tight-lipped.
I was not able to find out anything.
If they acted that way something must be very odd.
His Majesty has been thinking of Your Highness a lot.
He sent me to deliver these to Your Highness
as soon as we returned to the palace.
Thank you, Mr. Su.
I believe that you are capable of helping His Majesty conceal this from the harem.
Yes, I will do my best, Your Highness.
As for my father...
I understand, Your Highness.
If Your Highness mentions this to His Majesty directly,
he might suspect that you had
ulterior motives for your meeting the other day.
So I have taken an opportunity to bring this up.
His Majesty cares about Mr. Zhen because he knows you care about your father.
Even though Mr. Zhen has not been exonerated,
His Majesty sent an escort to Ningguta to
bring him back to the capital for medical treatment.
If all goes as planned, Mr. Zhen will arrive in Beijing soon.
How should I repay your kindness, Mr. Su?
How could I ask for a reward
for serving Your Highness?
In my current position,
I might not be able to offer what you request.
But, please don't feel obliged to decline me.
Your Highness flatters me too greatly.
I just did what little I'm capable of.
Your Majesty,
have you heard that recently His Majesty has been
offering incense at the Temple of Pure Dew more frequently?
The Temple of Pure Dew? Don't you know who lives there?
Didn't Autumn say that Zhen Huan no longer lives there?
I've heard that every time His Majesty goes,
he also visits Peak Lingyun, where Zhen Huan now resides.
It would seem that we have let our guard down after all.
Having close contacts with a banished concubine might damage His Majesty's prestige.
I wonder if Your Majesty has a plan?
A plan?
Such gossip is just baseless hearsay.
We'll watch how things unfold first.
What if Your Majesty requests to accompany
His Majesty when he visits the temple next time?
That might put Your Majesty's worries to rest.
If His Majesty insists on going there alone,
then there's nothing I can do about it.
We'll have to monitor the situation and develop a plan.
My Lady, Mr. Su is here.
Peace to Your Highness.
Please rise and have a seat.
- I thank Your Highness.
- Serve the tea, Jade
This is not a famous tea,
but it smells fresh.
I profusely thank Your Highness.
- Your Highness!
- My Lady.
What's wrong?
Mistress has been vomiting frequently these days.
Congratulations, Your Highness.
You are the first person to know, besides Jinxi and Jade.
Really?
May I ask how long Your Highness has been pregnant?
Just a little over a month.
Then it was the first time His Majesty came to Peak Lingyun.
Yes.
I would like to congratulate Your Highness on your timely conception.
This is surely a reason for Your Highness to return to the palace.
When His Majesty hears that I am with child,
he is likely to be overcome with excitement.
Please advise him to practice restraint.
Yes, yes, yes.
The Empress is in ill health
and troubled with matters in the palace.
You needn't bother others with the news of my pregnancy.
Yes, I understand.
I'll let only His Majesty know.
Your Highness is now pregnant.
We have to send a doctor to provide prenatal care.
Her Highness's status is still unclear.
So this could be awkward in a number of respects.
All the more reason the news should not be spread.
Dr. Wen Shichu from the Imperial Infirmary, however,
is on good terms with Her Highness.
Sending him to look after Her Highness
would be quite appropriate.
Jinxi, you've thought of everything! That's perfect.
His Majesty has always praised Dr. Wen's skills and kindliness.
I'm sure he will allow it.
Mr. Su, you have served His Majesty for a long time.
I trust you to know how to word it.
Yes.
I will be glad so long as I can deliver my child in peace
even if these mountains are remote and barren.
Your Highness must be joking.
How could His Majesty leave Your Highness here?
His Majesty will most certainly bring Your Highness back to the palace.
I left the palace as a banished concubine.
How could I be allowed to go back?
My only wish is that this child can grow up safely.
That would be enough.
What makes Your Highness say that?
You are carrying the imperial bloodline.
How could your child not be included in the imperial family?
His Majesty has always placed great importance on the imperial heirs.
He will deeply treasure your child.
It is my greatest fortune
that His Majesty treats me this way.
How dare I have desires beyond that?
But if His Majesty
granted my unborn child a title,
then even if I returned to the palace as a Companion,
I would shed tears of gratitude.
Your Highness must harm your health with sadness.
Please take care of yourself and the imperial heir.
I'll find a way to raise it with His Majesty.
It is urgent, but a very sensitive matter
and must not leak to anyone else.
Mistress is now alone outside the palace.
If anyone finds out that she's pregnant,
I can't imagine what trouble that might bring.
I understand the stakes. Jinxi, take good care of Her Highness.
I will report this to His Majesty
and send Dr. Wen for Your Highness's prenatal care.
Thank you, Mr. Su.
Allow me to take my leave.
Dr. Wen.
Mr. Su, what noble task has brought you here?
Let's not stand on ceremony, Dr. Wen.
I'm here today on His Majesty's orders,
with an assignment for you.
His Majesty has appointed you
to take care of a pregnant concubine.
Thank you for informing me, sir.
Which palace shall I attend to?
This concubine ... You are well acquainted already, Dr. Wen.
I am?
This concubine
currently resides at Peak Lingyun.
Is it ...?
This is a special assignment from His Majesty.
No one else can know about it.
Do you understand what I mean by this?
I understand, sir.
Dr. Wen.
Look at you sweating all over.
Sit down and drink some tea.
I don't feel like having tea.
Your father has returned to Beijing to receive medical treatment.
Su Peisheng sent Xiao-Xiazi
to bring a doctor from the Imperial Infirmary.
Su Peisheng is His Majesty's direct servant.
Why would he suddenly bring your father back to Beijing?
Since you already know,
why bother asking me?
Did Su Peisheng tell you ...
that I am with child?
Did he ask you to take care of me, and the child?
Did he say that I've been pregnant for only a month,
rather than the two months you know it to be?
Huan'er...
Why? What happened?
Because I met with His Majesty.
My child...
belongs to His Majesty.
That's why Su Peisheng sent you to tend to my prenatal care.
But this child clearly belongs to -
It doesn't matter who this child belongs to.
What matters is that His Majesty thinks this is his child
and that I have only been pregnant for just over a month.
Are you insane?
It's a crime to deceive His Majesty! What if...
There's no "what if".
The only "what if"
is what if you refuse to help me.
Go tell His Majesty
that I've been pregnant for over two months,
and that the child is not his!
You know I wouldn't!
Huan'er, I've told you before,
if you give birth to this child,
I will take care of you both for the rest of my life.
What do you have to worry about?
You might be able to take care of me and my child.
But could you have brought my father back for
treatment when he fell gravely ill in Ningguta?
Could you protect my whole family from any future harm?
Could you help me to investigate
and avenge Yunli's death?
I am not capable of any of those things, after all.
I would not be able to help you.
It is not your incapability.
It is my ill fate.
I finally escaped from the Forbidden City.
But now I still have to go back.
Because all under Heaven belongs to His Majesty.
No one else can help me as much as he can.
I wouldn't choose this
if there were another way.
Help me if you want to,
but I won't force you to.
The path ahead is already difficult for me and my child.
But however difficult it is,
even if every step forward will lead to my death,
I will protect my child.
But, even if I help you,
I can only help you back to the old path,
the same old life in the palace.
Huan'er, that path will be so difficult.
I have no one to rely on outside the palace.
I can only sit here and await death.
Even if I have endless struggles in the palace,
it's better than being murdered
here without even putting up a fight.
Shichu,
there are some things that you don't want to do.
I don't want to either.
But when things come to a head,
I am not free from cares.
I'm not free to go where I desire.
If I had known it would come to this,
I'd rather you never knew
about Noble Prince Guo's death.
All right then, Huan'er.
In this world, you're the only one I can't refuse.
There's nothing I can do to help you
but listen to you and aid in your plan.
Since you wish to protect others,
I will protect you with all my might.
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
Dr. Wen,
how is her condition?
Your Majesty, Concubine Sourire is already one month pregnant.
However...
What is wrong?
Her Highness's prenatal qi seems unstable
and undisturbed rest is needed.
To be safe, it would be prudent
to avoid intimate contact with her.
Spare no effort to take care of Concubine Sourire.
After the Infirmary takes attendance at five,
you will have no other tasks there.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
- You may rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Jinxi, bring me some water.
Your Majesty.
There is no need for such formality.
When did Your Majesty come?
I wasn't even aware of your arrival.
Jinxi, why didn't you wake me up?
His Majesty has been here for an hour already
but didn't want to wake Your Highness from your restful sleep.
I was the one who told Jinxi not to wake you up
so you could sleep longer.
Su Peisheng told you me are pregnant.
I'm absolutely delighted.
Your Majesty,
even if you were pleased
you needn't have come here today.
The rain has made the mountain roads difficult to traverse.
Your Majesty didn't need to rush over here.
Your pregnancy is the most joyful news.
I'm very happy.
You are also very blessed,
becoming pregnant from my first visit.
Your Majesty.
I say that because I'm worried.
Dr. Wen said your pregnancy is unstable
and many things are not allowed.
I'm very worried about you.
Si Lang, it's my fault for making you worry about me.
With everything going on in the palace,
if you weren't pregnant,
I'd have nothing to be happy about.
Here,
I had them prepare some bird's nest soup and heat it up here with some milk.
It was always your favorite.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Endless Longing is still in your possession.
In the three years since you left,
no one else has played music as expressively as you did.
What's wrong? Why are you tearing up?
I haven't played Endless Longing in a long time.
This feels like another life now.
Now that you are by my side again,
I also feel like ages have passed.
Return to the palace with me.
Your Majesty, I am a banished concubine
and an inauspicious presence.
Although I am pregnant with an imperial heir,
I do not think I deserve to return to the palace.
You were banished, but I can confer a new title on you.
So you can come back with me.
Won't the Empress Dowager disapprove?
I doubt the Empress Dowager will forbid it
knowing you are pregnant.
I will make all the necessary arrangements for you.
What? You said Zhen Huan is pregnant?
I am certain.
I saw with my own eyes that Dr. Wen
was preparing prenatal herbs,
but no concubine in the palace is pregnant.
Only the one at Peak Lingyun has the privilege
of being looked after by Dr. Wen.
Leave now.
Yes.
Despite our careful measures, we still
weren't able to defend against that minx's belly.
It would have been all right if she weren't pregnant.
But her conceiving a child so soon ... makes everything difficult.
Your Majesty,
we finally restored peace in the harem.
If Zhen Huan comes back with a child,
it might cause great disturbances in the palace.
Your Majesty, you must think of a way.
Although there is no precedent for a banished concubine to return,
I will still find other ways to stop her.
For the time being, we must keep her out of the palace,
so that we can "cut the roots to eliminate the weed."
Your Majesty, terrible news!
the Empress Dowager had a fainting episode again.
Quickly, order Baohua Hall to pray for Her Majesty.
Yes.
Also, get everything prepared for me to
offer incense tomorrow morning
and pray for Her Majesty.
My Lady, will the raw silk wrapping be bad for the baby?
It shouldn't be.
Dr. Wen told me about Consort Wang of Emperor Ling of Han.
Fearing Empress He's powers,
Consort Wang daren't mention her pregnancy.
She wrapped her stomach every day until just before birth.
Besides, I am only wrapping once every two or three days.
And it will only be for two or three months.
I won't make it too tight.
Dr. Wen also prescribed some stablizing tonics.
Wearing this loose-fitting robe,
you do look just about one month pregnant.
As long as His Majesty does not get intimate with me,
I can "cross the ocean without Heaven's notice."
Dr. Wen, do you have news of Huan'er?
She did ask me to deliver a message.
What is it?
Huan'er ... She's pregnant.
His Majesty may allow her to return.
Really?
However, this requires more than His Majesty's approval.
It also needs a nod from the Empress Dowager.
You attend the Empress Dowager every day.
If the Empress Dowager mentions this matter,
please put in a good word for Huan'er.
Yes, yes, of course.
Returning to the palace is just the beginning.
The road ahead is still long and arduous.
Your Highness needs to be prepared.
Once the Empress and An Lingrong
learn Your Highness is returning,
they will not back down easily.
His Majesty has made an ironclad decision.
It's unlikely the Empress can reverse it.
So she might "help launch the boat into the current,"
knowing it leads to treacherous rapids ahead.
Once I am back,
she will use her power as head of the
harem to scheme against me.
That will be hard to counter.
I never expected her power
to be unchecked for all these years.
Her luck is about to end!
But even if she attempts something, it will be futile.
If My Lady returns as a Consort,
and gives birth in a few months,
your position will be securely rooted.
By then, you will have the ability to contend with her, if you wish.
I only hope that after you return to opulence and luxury, My Lady,
you do not forget the hatred in our hearts.
Mistress, help!
The Consort Dowager...
She heard the news of His Lordship's death from Ajin,
and has refused to eat for three days and nights.
She won't listen to anybody.
Bring me to see Her Venerable Highness.
Please leave us for a moment, madam.
I will accompany Her Venerable Highness.
The dead have passed on.
Do the living ...
have to join them?
There isn't a moment that I haven't wanted to join Yunli.
Ending my life would put an end to it all,
leaving me with no more worries.
Would Your Venerable Highness care only for your son,
not your grandson?
The child in my belly
is waiting to call Your Venerable Highness grandmother.
The child has lost his father.
Will Your Venerable Highness also leave him behind?
Your Majesty,
I had only one son with you.
But I didn't take good care of him.
Now...
"A gray-haired parent has to lament the black-haired child."
Yunli ... Yunli ...
You are going to be a father.
But you can't ...
You can't see your child.
Huan’er, you are with child.
Don't let grief overcome you.
Please stop crying.
Your Venerable Highness,
please have some food.
Yes.
I'll eat something.
Nebular,
bring in the meal.
Yes.
Your Venerable Highness,
I'm afraid...
I won't be able to visit here anymore.
Why?
His Majesty...
wants me to return to the palace to serve him.
I have agreed.
There's no harm ... in you returning to the palace.
And you can’t defy ... the Emperor's decree.
But the child in your belly…
His Majesty thinks...
the child is his.
so he insists that I return to the palace.
Yunli's body isn't even cold yet.
How can you...
make my grandson
call another man father?
Your Venerable Highness, did you know that
Yunli's death was not an accident.
He was murdered!
Someone tampered with his ship,
causing his death in the Yellow River.
I never thought Yunli's death was an accident!
He "died with unmet desires in his eyes."
I swear to avenge his murder.
How I wish I was not just a powerless woman...
But do you have to take my grandson to the palace?
I didn't want it to be this way either.
But this is the only way
that I can avenge Yunli's death
and protect our child.
And only this way
can I protect my family.
Your Venerable Highness, can you imagine
how much I want to go with Yunli
if I have to live like this.
But for Yunli, and for our child,
and also for the Zhen clan,
I have to do this,
no matter how difficult it is.
Let's leave.
What happened just now was inauspicious.
Don't tell anyone about it.
Your Majesty is in low spirits,
why not take a walk in the imperial garden?
Let's admire the fish by the bridge.
The Empress Dowager is acutely ill.
I am not in the mood to meander around.
Let's go back now.
Yes.
- Your Majesty!
- Are you all right, Your Majesty?
Go, call the doctor!
Call the doctor!
Your Majesty!
- It's on fire!
- Protect Her Majesty!
- Bring water!
- Save Her Majesty!
- Someone get help!
- Help Her Majesty!
- Fire! Help!
-Bring water!
Fire! The Palace of Longevity is on fire!
Hurry! There's a fire!
At the Palace of Longevity!
Fire! At the Palace of Longevity! Go!
You've always been composed and prudent.
How could you sprain your ankle?
It must be the carelessness of the servants.
It's not because of them.
I should have been more careful.
Fortunately, it's not very serious.
You investigated it. What happened?
The slate pavers show signs of loosening,
which caused Her Majesty to lose her footing.
It was just me being careless then.
But when Your Majesty was praying at Baohua Hall,
the incense broke twice, which is really inauspicious.
Don't talk nonsense.
Your Majesty, a fire was put out at the Palace of Longevity.
How come?
Did the Empress Dowager get hurt?
Her Majesty was unconscious
so she wasn't hurt or frightened.
Luckily the fire didn't spread before it was put out.
Good. I must visit Her Majesty.
Your Majesty,
I have something to say but I'm not sure if it's appropriate.
Say it.
Their Majesties have both a fright on the same day,
one had a sprained ankle, the other caught in a fire.
I feel unsettled.
Shouldn't we consult the Astrological Office?
I will first visit the Palace of Longevity.
Su Peisheng.
Your Majesty.
Summon the astrological officials
to the Hall of Mental Cultivation after dinner.
Aye.
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
Rise.
Today the Empress Dowager and the Empress
both encountered misfortunes,
one caught in a fire, the other spraining her ankle.
Are there any abnormal signs in Heaven?
I was going to report to Your Majesty.
While observing astrological phenomena over the past few nights,
I found that among the seven lunar mansions
of the Black Tortoise of the North,
the Roof mansion, which is supposed to illuminate in October,
suddenly brightened up.
Carrying a small star at the tail,
it has the momentum to impinge on the moon.
The Roof mansion?
Yes. It is a mansion in the north
which portends height and danger.
This astrological phenomenon is
highly inauspicious as it threatens the moon.
In the palace, the Empress Dowager
and the Empress are masters of the Moon.
Additionally, the small star on its tail
could signify a pregnant woman
residing in a place of elevation in the north.
This woman could endanger the well-being of
the Empress Dowager and the Empress.
Is this woman in the palace now?
Not presently.
From the star's trajectory towards the moon,
this woman is still outside of the palace,
but she is approaching.
Once she draws near Their Majesties,
the two masters of the Moon will be in danger.
A pregnant woman outside the palace?
High elevation in the north ...
Peak Lingyun.
North... outside the palace.
Su Peisheng.
The return of Concubine Sourire
can take a lower priority for now.
Yes.
Your Highness, Su Peisheng sent a message that
His Majesty is concerned about an astrological event:
the Roof mansion is impinging on the Moon,
so your return will have to be postponed.
I knew from the start
that it wouldn't be so easy to return to the palace.
That's fine. "Attacks and counterattacks."
It's better than not knowing what they're up to.
Tell Su Peisheng to inform Meizhuang
everything will be easier
if she can persuade the Empress Dowager.
Yes, I'll tell him now.
Mother, you sprained your ankle
and had a fright a few days ago.
I'm glad that you've recovered now.
Please be careful when you walk.
I was worried about you.
Luckily, it was nothing serious.
I’m feeling better after a few days' rest.
But being in the palace the whole time,
I’ve missed you.
It is my undeserved honor
that you were concerned about me.
Since your school finished early today,
we have some time for a chat.
Have you reviewed what your tutor taught you?
Yes, I have.
That’s good. As long as you put in the effort,
His Majesty will appreciate it.
"The way of great learning consists in manifesting one's bright virtue,"
"in loving the people, and in stopping in perfect goodness."
[The Great Learning: Translated by A. Charles Muller]
"The ancients who wanted to manifest their bright
virtue to all first governed well their own states."
"Those who wanted to rule other states
first unified their own clans."
Autumn, who’s taking care of the Fourth Prince now?
The elderly maids that came with him
from the Summer Palace.
Has His Majesty visited the Fourth Prince?
Except for asking about his studies,
His Majesty has never mentioned him.
Third Prince, you and the Fourth Prince study together,
how does he perform in class?
The tutor always says that although my brother started late,
he is intelligent and learns quickly.
What does your Imperial Father think?
Father rarely speaks with him.
How do you compare to the Fourth Prince?
Although he’s diligent, he started late,
There's still a lot he must learn, so
he can't compare to me.
That might be the case now,
But he’s working so hard after class,
and putting forth more effort than you do.
He puts his heart into study
and might achieve greatness one day.
"The Noble Man embodies the mean;
the petty man goes against it."
"The Noble Man embodies the mean because he is always with it."
[The Doctrine of the Mean: Translated by A. Charles Muller]
Fourth Prince, you had only a few bites
at dinner before coming to study...
Please be careful not to strain your eyes.
Don’t disturb me, Madam.
I’m worried about you.
You might fall ill if you keep working day and night.
I was fortunate to be able to come back to the palace.
Imperial Father asks me about my studies
every time he sees me.
If I can’t even do well with books,
no one will respect me.
Fourth Prince, your late-night snack is ready.
Put it here.
Fourth Prince, I asked them
to prepare mung bean soup for you,
It's good for your eyes.
Please have some before you continue.
I don’t want it. You can have it, Madam.
I had it made for you ...
How would I dare to drink it?
If you drank some, you would talk less.
I won't sleep until I memorize this text tonight.
But…
Drink it!
Yes.
Madam… What's going on?
Madam!
Madam! What happened?
The Fourth Prince! What… What happened?
Don’t be afraid, Fourth Prince.
I’m Concubine Vertu from the Palace of Pearl Jade.
The Palace of Pearl Jade?
Yes.
Someone is trying to kill me!
Fourth Prince, you cannot say nonsense like that!
I'm not speaking nonsense,
My maid's body is lying in the Yueshi Opera House, where I live.
Your Highness, please save me!
- Yes, yes.
- Please save me!
Fourth Prince, don't be frightened.
If you trust me, I will think of a way to help you.
Peace to the Imperial Grandmother.
Fourth Prince, what brings you here?
"A man does not easily shed his tears."
Why are you crying?
Come here, come to Grandmother.
Please don't blame the Fourth Prince for crying.
He was running as if he lost his soul.
Your Majesty, the Fourth Prince's maid
accidentally ate his mung bean soup
and died immediately in front of him...
What?
Grandmother, I know that I'm not liked because of my low status,
but I have never borne anyone ill will.
Why does someone want me dead?
I was thinking
the Fourth Prince doesn't have his mother
in the palace to look after him.
For his safety,
I plead with Your Majesty
to allow the Fourth Prince
to stay in the Palace of Longevity.
I'm obligated to.
Good grandson,
what filth you have witnessed.
You must be terrified.
Regarding the murder of the Fourth Prince's maid,
should it be further pursued?
That might be too difficult I'm afraid.
A single bowl of mung bean soup
could have been passed through many hands.
If the investigation escalates,
this would be a scandal in the palace.
I agree with Your Majesty.
Your Majesty and the Empress have been affected by the
impingement of the Roof mansion on Moon.
Concubine Sourire cannot return to the palace
and must stay outside with an imperial heir.
If this goes on, the imperial lineage might be compromised.
Is it the Moon that is being impinged upon,
or the imperial heirs?
Orchid,
Move the Fourth Prince's belongings to the Palace of Longevity.
The Fourth Prince will stay here for now.
I dare anyone to harm him.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I will take the Fourth Prince to his chamber to rest,
and then collect his belongings.
Grandmother, I shall take my leave.
You may leave as well.
Yes, I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Bamboo,
who do you think made this attempt
to harm the Fourth Prince's life?
Your Majesty's mind is a clear mirror.
I dare not speak nonsense
to disturb Your Majesty's judgement.
In the palace, aside from her,
who else would care about the Fourth Prince's presence?
But the Empress has the Third Prince as her son,
she shouldn't have a reason to do this.
It's precisely because she has a foster son
that she wants to clear his way to the Crown.
The Empress is becoming more and more unscrupulous.
No one in the harem can check her.
If it goes on like this,
I'm afraid that the imperial bloodline will wither.
Bamboo,
ask the Emperor to come here tomorrow.
Yes.
The Fourth Prince survived?
It was the Fourth Prince's maid who died.
Incompetent!
My offense deserves death, Your Majesty.
Please punish me.
Withdraw immediately. Clear any traces.
No further moves until everyone lets down their guard.
Yes.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.